<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charlotte's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Thomas Elrod and Lars Hedenborg, top Real Estate Agents in Charlotte, shares their own internal real estate agent training for free. Their Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>BeBetterCharlotte.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="BeBetterCharlotte.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:29:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:29:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Went From 3 Transactions in 2011 to 230 in 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s5EAqPsIKzs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let me share a story with you about a tip I learned that changed my real estate career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I entered the real estate business in April 2010 and initially stumbled my way through it. About a year later, in April 2011, a fellow agent swung by my office and told me they noticed I was working hard, but they weren’t sure if I was working smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked that agent to explain what they meant, they asked me, “Do you know the difference between working on your business and working in your business?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said no and told them they both sounded the same. As it turns out, &lt;strong&gt;there’s a huge difference between working on your business and working in your business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you work in your business, you work with buyers and sellers, showing houses, writing contracts, etc. We call this the PLAN method—the “P” stands for prospecting, the “L” stands for lead follow-up, the “A” stands for appointments, and the “N” stands for negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in the business is what I was doing that day. It was a Tuesday morning in April and I was designing a brochure for a listing I’d just taken. I was also working on my Zillow profile and doing some other things that weren’t income-producing. We refer to these things as DPAs: dollar-producing activities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Working on your business means working on the things that build your business%20BeBetterCharlotte.com/how-i-went-from-3-transactions-in-2011-to-230-in-2017.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Working on your business means working on the things that build your business”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on your business, on the other hand, means working on the things that build your business—marketing, expenses, branding, etc. By learning the difference between these two concepts, I realized that I needed to be working in the business from 8 a.m. to 8 p.m. and working on the business either before 8 a.m. or after 8 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The minute I implemented this plan, my career took off.&lt;/strong&gt; I went from having only three transactions in 2010 to having 21 in 2011. Then from 21 to 27 in 2012. Then from 27 to 75 in 2013. Then from 75 to 128 in 2014. Then from 128 to 151 in 2015. Then from 151 to 175 in 2016. Finally, in 2017, I went from 175 to 230 transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I share this information with you isn’t to brag. I have a Ph.D. in DUMB when it comes to real estate—I’ve done every dumb thing you can possibly imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about how how we train our agents to reach their highest performance level possible, don’t hesitate to call or email us. We’d love to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:53:40 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>BeBetterCharlotte.com/how-i-went-from-3-transactions-in-2011-to-230-in-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">BeBetterCharlotte.com/how-i-went-from-3-transactions-in-2011-to-230-in-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Tips to Ensure Your Buyer’s Offer Is Accepted</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bu-sqMnntVo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, we are definitely in a sellers market. We’re seeing 10 to 12 offers and 50 to 60 showings in just days after listing a home. With that in mind, I want to give you eight tips to help you get your buyer’s offer accepted in a multiple offer seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the buyer fully pre-approved, not just pre-qualified.&lt;/strong&gt; As a listing agent, when I receive a buyer’s agent’s offer to purchase in contract with a pre-qualification, I get a little concerned. A pre-approval is much better. Pre-qualification means that they’ve run your Equifax, Experian, or TransUnion credit score. Even if they have a great score, there are a lot of stipulations they need to get to the lender, such as two years’ worth of tax return, bank statement, blood type, hair follicles, and so on (just kidding about those last two). You want to be sure that they’re fully pre-approved to protect the seller at the highest level.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A heartfelt letter to the seller.&lt;/strong&gt; Have your buyers write a letter directly to the seller, stating why they love the property so much and what appeals to the buyer. Hit the seller’s hot buttons. It’s important to show the seller that there’s emotion there; they want to be sure their house is going to be a great home for the new buyers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submit an offer that’s 5% to 10% over the asking price.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a common tactic in the market right now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make an agreement to pay 5% to 10% over the appraised value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An obnoxious due diligence fee and earnest money deposit&lt;/strong&gt; will definitely help motivate the sellers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a shorter time period for home inspections, appraisal, and closing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid offers contingent on appraisals and home inspections&lt;/strong&gt;, unless there is major structural damage, radon, mold, or termites.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving the seller possession after closing a week to 30 days at no charge.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers don’t feel very comfortable moving their stuff out of a property before closing, only to find out that the buyer’s deal falls through. Giving that seller possession after closing definitely gives them more peace of mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A pre-approval is much better than a pre-qualification.%20BeBetterCharlotte.com/8-tips-to-ensure-your-buyers-offer-is-accepted.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A pre-approval is much better than a pre-qualification.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about how we train our high-performance agents at the highest level, feel free to reach out to us. We’d love to sit down and talk with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:50:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>BeBetterCharlotte.com/8-tips-to-ensure-your-buyers-offer-is-accepted.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">BeBetterCharlotte.com/8-tips-to-ensure-your-buyers-offer-is-accepted.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
